准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
丢失的身份
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
小餐馆
纵横字谜
不好  我笔丢了
Oh, no, I lost my pen
可以借我的
You can borrow mine
谢了
Thanks
我曾经也丢过一次东西
I lost something once
我丢过一辈子离不开的东西
I lost something I couldn't live without
我的身份
My identity
总之  谢谢你借我笔
So anyway, thanks for the pen
没关系
No problem, hon
一切都要从上周说起
It all started last week
准确来说是上周一早上
Monday morning to be exact
我正是在那天丢失了身份
The day I lost my identity
我得走了
I got to go
早安  世界
Good morning, world
还有住在世界里的大家
and all who inhabit it
小蜗  救命
Gary, help
我看不见了
I can't see
小蜗
Gary
小蜗  你在吗
Gary, are you there?
小蜗
Gary?
小蜗  兄弟
Gary, buddy?
我要你来当我眼睛  好不好
I need you to be my eyes, okay?
我离卫生间近吗
Am I near the bathroom?
小蜗
Gary?
Gar?
小蜗
Gary
既然我这场可怕事件结束了
Now that my horrific incident of terror is over
要不要来吃早餐啊
how 'bout some breakfast?
一天当中最重要的一餐
The most important meal of the day
端出小蜗一贯的口味
Serving it up Gary's way
小蜗
请慢用  兄弟
Enjoy, buddy
我喂小蜗这么多年了
You know, I've been feeding this to Gary for years
连蜗牛粮什么味道都不知道
and I don't even know what it tastes like
蜗牛粮
世界总部
怎么了  彼得森
What is it, Peterson?
不太确定
I'm not sure
感觉我
I feel
有点不适
a disturbance
刚刚那是我吃过最难吃的东西了
That was the worst thing I've ever tasted
好吧  至少再也不会吃这玩意了
Oh, well, at least I'll never have to do it again
真见鬼
Barnacles
刚刚那一堆把戏害我上班快迟到了
All these shenanigans made me late for work
好了
All right
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
等一下
Wait a minute
你身份到底什么时候丢的
When exactly did you lose your identity?
对啊  谁又是派大星
Yeah, and who's Patrick?
你为什么要吃蜗牛粮
Why did you eat Snail-Po?
耐心一点  两位善人
Patience, good people
好故事的节奏可不能赶
A great story can't be rushed
不过我要直接跳到蟹堡王那段
However, I will skip ahead to The Krusty Krab
上菜了
Order up
一份蟹黄堡
One Krabby Patty
以我炽热的真心温热烤制而成
grilled with the fiery warmth of my beating heart
请慢用
Enjoy
谢了
Thanks
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem?
你真应该戴一个身份牌
Well, you really should be wearing a name tag
方便我好好感谢你
so I can thank you properly
虽然与客人产生分歧有违我的原则
While it is against my philosophy
to disagree with a customer
但我必须指出
I must point out
我其实戴着一个身份牌
that I am, in fact, wearing a name tag
就在这里
right here
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
章鱼哥  太可怕了
Oh, Squidward, it's terrible
最可怕的事就这样发生在我身上了
It's the most terrible thing that's ever happened to me
我身份牌弄丢了
I lost my name tag
为什么
Pourquoi?
海绵宝宝  别激动
SpongeBob, take it easy
你可以再弄一个新的身份牌
I'm sure you can get a new one
可我不要新身份牌  章鱼哥
But I don't want a new one, Squidward
我的身份牌肯定就在这附近
My name tag is out there somewhere
走失
Lost
又挨饿
Hungry
谁会伸出援手
Who will help it?
万一被谁用了呢
What if someone's using it?
银行
全都不许动
All right, nobody move
海绵宝宝
这可是银行抢劫
This is a bank robbery
阿提卡
Attica
[ 本台词改自电影《热天午后》相关情节
指1971年阿提卡监狱暴动事件 ]
跟你说  我是无辜的
I'm innocent, I tell ya
奢华生活
文摘
章鱼哥  怎么了
Squidward, what happened?
你晕倒了
You fainted
因为你刚弄丢了身份牌什么的
because you lost your name tag or something
海绵宝宝  你能不能镇静一点
SpongeBob, will you get ahold of yourself?
什么时候把身份牌弄丢
Since when is losing your name tag
搞得连天都要塌了
the end of the world?
全体员工请注意
Attention, all employees
稍微提醒一下  小子们
Just a quick heads-up, boys
一小时后有仪容仪表突击检查
There's going to be a surprise
uniform inspection in one hour
但凡检查没通过的都会被开除
Anyone who doesn't pass, gets the boot
得 到 靴 子
而这个靴子呢
This boot, to be exact
非常臭
It's very stinky
必须要穿一整天
and you have to wear it all day
一小时后见
See you in an hour
海绵宝宝  如果你真想
SpongeBob, if you really want
找到你的身份牌  就重走来时路
to find your name tag, just retrace your steps
重走来时路吗
Retrace my steps?
章鱼哥  你真是个天才
Squidward, you're a genius
天才
A genius
我都不知道  不过
Well, I don't know about that, but
你帮我代班  我等会回来
Cover me till I get back, okay?
可以
Sure, sure
天才
A genius
要不然就
Well, how about
我想想
Let's see
要想重走来时路
If I'm going to retrace my steps
就必须回忆今早做过的所有事
I got to remember everything I did this morning
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
你今早向我说过嗨  对吧
You said hi to me this morning, right?
我每早都这样
As I do every morning
我要你再说一次
Well, I need you to do it again
我可没这个义务  海绵宝宝
That wasn't part of the deal, Squarepants
派大星  你在胡说什么
Patrick, what are you talking about?
我的问候可不是什么录音
My hellos aren't just some tape recording
又不能供你倒带  一遍遍重放
that you can rewind and play over and over
那可是特别的东西
They're special
派大星  这可是紧急情况
Patrick, this is an emergency
我今早丢了身份牌
I lost my name tag this morning
得重走来时路
and I need to retrace my steps
你丢了身份牌吗
You lost your name tag?
派大星  你应该知道计划吧
Okay, Patrick, you know the plan, right?
我知道  我知道
I got it, I got it
你要重走来时路
You're going to retrace your steps
等到你路过我
and when you walk by me
我就会像今早那样说嗨
I say, "Hi," just like this morning
很好
Perfect
看来得直接重走到醒来的那会儿
I guess I should start with when I woke up
但愿会有用
I sure hope this works
早安  世界
Good morning, world
还有住在世界里的大家
and all who inhabit it
目前为止还算顺利
So far, so good
没在上面看到我身份牌
I don't see my name tag up here
既然我这场可怕事件结束了
Now that my horrific incident of terror is over
要不要来吃早餐啊
how 'bout some breakfast?
一天当中最重要的一餐
The most important meal of the day
端出小蜗一贯的口味
Serving it up Gary's way
好了
Okay
接下来就只要走出门
Next I just have to walk outside
跟派大星说嗨
and say hi to Patrick
派大星
Patrick
干嘛
What?
你应该要跟我说声嗨的
You were supposed to say hi to me
嗨
Hi
好  从头再来吧
All right, let's take it from the top
再见  海绵宝宝
Bye, SpongeBob
这回可别忘了念你台词
Don't forget your line this time
不会忘的
I won't
早安  世界
Good morning, world
还有住在世界里的大家
and all who inhabit it
一天当中最重要的一餐
The most important meal of the day
小蜗的口味
Gary's way
派大星  怎么不跟我说嗨
Patrick, why didn't you say hi to me?
我动力是什么
What's my motivation?
别管动力了
Forget the motivation
说嗨就对了
Just say hi
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
等等
Wait
我才是派大星
I'm Patrick
对不起
I'm sorry
抱歉
Sorry
对不起
I'm sorry
再来一次吧
Let's try it again
嗨  海绵卜卜
Hi, SpongeBoob
海绵卜卜
SpongeBoob?
我  我说了
I-I said
谁是海绵卜卜
Who's SpongeBoob?
我说了海绵卜卜
I said SpongeBoob
再来再来
Again, again
大家抱歉
Sorry, people
一天当中最重要的一餐
The most important meal of the day
小蜗的口味
Gary's way
我笑场了
I got the giggles
又有什么用
What's the use?
这下没法及时找到身份牌应对检查了
I'll never find my name tag in time for inspection
我今早跟你说嗨后  你做什么了
Well, what did you do after I said hi to you this morning?
我想想
Let's see
我高高兴兴跳去了蟹堡王
I skipped merrily to The Krusty Krab
跟老头简金斯问好
Said hello to old man Jenkins
嗨  老简
Hi, Mr. J
往蟹老板桌上放了个苹果
Placed an apple on Mr. Krabs's desk
就差不多了
and that's about it
还有俩人把我丢垃圾箱里
And these two guys threw me in the dumpster
你们可真好笑
Good one, guys
就这样了
That's it
你身份牌就在蟹老板桌上的苹果里
Your name tag is in the apple on Mr. Krabs' desk
派大星  你真是个天才
Patrick, you're a genius
等下  苹果现在可能被扔掉了
Wait, he's probably thrown it away by now
那就到垃圾箱里面找
Well, then, we'll look in the dumpster
什么臭味啊
What is that stench?
那是发现之味
That is the stench of discovery
来吧  兄弟
Come on, buddy
我推你一把
I'll give you a boost
上来吧
Hop on, pal
习惯之后就没那么臭了
It's not so bad, once you get used to it
真希望我长了鼻子
I wish I had a nose
进来吧  兄弟
Come on in, buddy
垃圾的温度刚刚好呢
the garbage is fine
炮弹来了
Cannonball
你那边找
You look over there
我这边找
and I'll look over here
好
Okay
派大星
Patrick
在找了  在找了
I'm looking, I'm looking
派大星
Patrick
我尽快在找了
I'm looking as fast as I can
派大星
Patrick
谢谢
Thank you
让我来拿
Here, let me get that
快看
Look
有张刺魟5000的单曲
A Stingray 5000 single
这伙人可酷了
These guys rock
怎么会有谁想把这种宝贝丢掉呢
Why would anybody throw this away?
刺魟5000
你是不是忘了我们在找什么
Have you forgotten what we're looking for
怎么还沉迷在昨日前40金曲中了
knee deep in yesterday's Top 40 songs?
确实忘了
Yes
给你个提示  两个词
I'll give you a hint: Two words
第一个词  我的
First word, "my"
第二个词  身份牌
Second word, "name tag"
能再来个提示吗
Could I have another hint?
派大星  我很想傻坐在这里
Patrick, I would love to sit here
陪你玩问答游戏
and play "20 Questions" with you
可是离检查就只差一分钟了
but I've only got one minute till inspection
就一分钟吗
One minute?
赶紧  派大星
Hurry, Patrick
时间不多了
We don't have much time
海绵宝宝
Hey, SpongeBob
现在没空  派大星
Not now, Patrick
我知道你身份牌在哪了
I know where your name tag is
在哪
Where?
想不起来了
I can't remember
派大星  我没空陪你这么闹
Patrick, I don't have time for this
找到了
There it is
在哪
Where?
我又忘了
I forgot again
派大星  你到底在挺我还是损我
Patrick, are you with me or against me?
能不能给我个提示
Well, could you give me a hint?
在那
There
我看到了
I see it
好好好
Yeah, yeah, yeah
大喊身份牌的小朋友
The boy who cried, "Name tag"
如果你不打算帮我忙
If you're not going to help me
麻烦你爬回你石头底下去
then just go crawl back under your rock
起码我自己不会穿反衣服
Well, at least I don't wear my shirt backwards
穿反衣服
My shirt backward?
怎么
What the?
我衣服穿反了
My shirt's on backwards
原来我的身份一直都在
I had my identity all along
正好赶上了
And just in time
谢了  派大星
Thanks, Patrick
不用谢  兄弟
Don't mention it, buddy
全体集合  准备检查
Fall in for inspection
好了  你们两个
All right, you two
帽子和制服看着很整洁
Hat and uniform seem to be in order
向我保证今晚会刮鼻子  你就过了
Promise me you'll shave tonight and you pass
万岁
Hoo-rah
小子  到你了
Okay, boy, your turn
保证你会发现一切整洁
I think you'll find everything ship-shape
我的水母啊  什么臭味啊
Jumping jellyfish, what's that stench?
发现之味
Discovery?
于是  我找回了我的身份
And that's how I got my identity back
我的故事讲完了
Welp, that's my story
你正好打发了11分钟时间
Well, you managed to kill 11 minutes
谢了
Thanks, uh
需要服务吗
贝蒂
Betty
什么
What?
我又不是贝蒂
Sweetie, I'm not Betty
我只是借了她的制服
I just borrowed her uniform
我自己的制服拿去干洗了
while mine's at the cleaners
痞老板的军队
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
啊  蟹堡王
Ah, The Krusty Krab
内有美味的蟹黄堡
home of the delicious Krabby Patty
以及蟹堡王的超机密配方
and its super-secret recipe
请注意  蟹堡王的员工们
Attention, Krusty Krab crew
全体成员立刻报到
All hands report immediately
煎炸厨师海绵宝宝报到  老板
Fry Cook SpongeBob reporting, sir
到底在喊什么啊
What's all the yelling about?
今天可是25周年纪念日
Today is the 25th anniversary
纪念我的死对头痞老板第一次
of the first time me archenemy Plankton
前来偷我的蟹黄堡秘密配方
ever tried to steal me secret Krabby Patty formula
秘方能给我吗
Can I have the secret formula?
不能
No
好吧
Okay
但他坚持不懈
But he was persistent
拜托了
Pretty please?
他用过伪装
He used disguise
超科学
Super-science
我不是蟑螂
非暴力反抗运动
civil disobedience
但我总是占得上风
and I always came out on top
太迷人了
Fascinating
但他失败了那么多次  变得诡计多端
But thousands of failures have made him crafty
所以务必严加提防
so keep your eyes open
你们永远不知道他会用什么诡计
You never know what trick he'll use
来偷取我的蟹黄堡秘密配方
to steal me secret Krabby Patty formula
真是个古雅的餐厅
What a quaint restaurant
我要采样他们的货品
I think I will sample their wares
真奇怪
How weird
做成顾客模样的机器人
A machine made to look like a customer
海绵宝宝  你去冲一下男厕所
SpongeBob, why don't you go hose out the men's room
没问题  老板
With pleasure, sir
我来应付这位
I'll take this one
欢迎光临蟹堡王  先生
Welcome to The Krusty Krab, sir
需要服务吗
May I help you?
需要
Yes, please
我要点一份辣珊瑚块
I'd like an order of chili coral bits
你确定不要蟹黄堡吗
You sure you don't want a Krabby Patty?
不用  谢谢
No, thank you
这点够付吗
Will this cover it?
够
Sure
拿去吧
Here you go
再见
Good day
这肯定是痞老板的诡计
I was sure it was one of Plankton's tricks
起码他的钱能用
Well, at least his money's good
痞老板
Plankton
你明知道我永不怀疑金钱的
You knew I would never distrust a dollar
没错  老螃蟹
That's right, Krabs
马上给我交出蟹黄堡的秘密配方
Now, hand over the secret Krabby Patty formula
不然怎么样
Or what?
不知道
I don't know
我都没想过会走到这一步
I never thought I'd get this far
那我来指点你下一步怎么走
Well, then, allow me to suggest your next move
我诅咒你  老螃蟹
Curse you, Krabs
现在来喝点带劲儿的
And now for the chaser
裤头村市
等着瞧  老螃蟹
You just wait, Krabs
下次我会
Next time I'll
我在逗谁啊
Who am I kidding?
海之霸
起码回家还有通情达理的老婆
At least I can go home to a wife who understands
那么  说说看怎么了
So, tell me what happened
我完全不想说
I don't want to talk about it
说出来就踏实多了
Talking will make you feel better
别来烦我
Leave me alone
你就是这种问题
That's your problem
什么事都憋在心里
You never let anyone in
你非要当顽石  非要当独行侠
Plankton the rock, Plankton the loner
她又来了  女士们先生们
And she's off, ladies and gentlemen
你非要亲力亲为
You have to do everything yourself
所以你不管做什么都是这个下场
That's why everything you try ends up like this
还有这个下场
And like this
最近是这个下场
And more recently, like this
我是个废物
I'm a failure
才没那么废
It's not that bad
你只是需要一点帮助
You just require a little help
不然找点打手
Maybe some henchmen
打手
Henchmen?
对
Yes
你就只要
What you need to do
在身边多招一点雄壮肌肉男
is surround yourself with muscular tough guys
让他们听你指挥就行
who will do whatever you say
这么说还不错
I like the sound of that
这就到全镇所有肮脏文盲小会所游说
I'll canvass all the seediest lowbrow dives in town
寻找我的小喽啰
to find my minions
我正好会说他们的语言
And I know just how to speak their language
祝贺大家  各位犯罪分子
Felicitations, malefactors
我正在拼尽全力盗取
I am endeavoring to misappropriate
廉价食品所需的配方
the formulary for the preparation
of affordable comestibles
谁想跟我一起来
Who will join me?
我不明白
I don't get it
不管我做什么
No matter what I do
最后的下场都是被比我大的人踩扁
I always end up
being squashed by someone bigger than me
拜托
Come on
你多半是过激了
I think you're overreacting
抱歉
Sorry
没事
That's okay
我跟海底其他数百万浮游生物没两样
I'm no different than the millions of
other plankton in the sea
左腿
右腿
浮游生物家族
The plankton family
长久以来受人摆布  又任人践踏
has always been pushed around and stepped on
等等
Wait
有了
That's it
虽然单打独斗确实力量微弱
Acting alone, we're powerless
但只要联合起来  浮游生物家族
but united, the plankton family
就会是眼中钉肉中刺
could be a real pain in the belly
电话簿
老螃蟹多半以为一只浮游生物好对付
Krabs may think one plankton is no problem
浮游生物
倒要来看看他能不能对付两只
but let's see him take on two
或者十只
or ten
或者一百只
or 100
或者一千只
or 1,000
何止如此
And why stop there?
我要召集天涯海角所有家族成员
I'll gather every family member
亲爱的浮游生物
你好吗
from every corner of the ocean
让整个浮游生物家族
The entire plankton family
聚在同一个屋檐下
under one roof
呼叫全体浮游生物
老螃蟹绝对没办法
Krabs won't stand a chance
敌得过我这一大队智囊
against the staggering intellect
多达百万的高智商犯罪智多星大军
of a million super-smart criminal masterminds
他们来了
They're here
欢迎各位同胞
Welcome, brethren
快看  兄弟
Look here, buddy
是痞老表
It's Cousin Plankton
原来我离家久得连我都记不清了
I've been away from home longer than I thought
你好啊  老表
Well, howdy, cousin
是我  克莱姆
It's me, Clem
当然  你肯定记得齐克
Of course, you remember Zeke
鲁弗斯  吉特
Rufus, Jete
比利鲍勃  比利吉姆
Billy Bob, Billy Jim
比利比利波维利巴那那法那佛菲利
Billy Billy Bo Willy Banana Fana Fo Filly
道格  伊那斯
Doug, Enos
朱利欧  弗莱彻麦基
Julio, Fletcher McGee
雷恩柴尔德
Rainchild
好了  我都知道
All right, I get it
我是说
I mean, uh
请进  大家别客气
come inside, make yourself at home
给大家认识一下我的电脑老婆凯伦
I'd like you to meet my computer wife, Karen
天啊
Golly
她可真漂亮  谢尔顿
she sure is pretty, Sheldon
谢尔顿吗
Sheldon?
对  我真名就叫那个
Yes, that's my first name
谢尔顿
Sheldon?
你能不能
Will you please?
抱歉
I'm sorry
好了
All right
我刚刚说到
as I was saying
好  谢尔顿这名字确实很好笑
Okay, we all know Sheldon's a funny name
好
O-ho-kay
好  笑完了
Okay, I'm done
不会再笑了
No more
好
Good
继续说
To continue
只有你们能将荣耀
Only you can bring honor
谢尔顿
与尊严
And dignity
谢尔顿
带回浮游生物家族
Back to the plankton
谢尔顿
多年以来  我的目标就是
For years, it has been my goal
谢尔顿
得到秘方  当作
to acquire the secret formula for
都给我得了
Okay, that's enough
谢尔顿
Sheldon
重点
Bottom line
我们入侵蟹堡王
we invade The Krusty Krab
让我偷到秘密配方
so I can steal the secret formula
怎么样
What do you think?
对我们有什么好处
What's in it for us?
我们呢
What about us?
那你们想要什么
Well, what do you want?
能给我班卓琴换根新弦吗
Could I get a new string for my banjo?
能找到跟这只相配的靴子吗
And another boot to match this 'un?
能给我笔记本电脑加点内存吗
And some more memory for my laptop?
还有根啤呢
What about root beer?
根啤
Root beer?
帮我把秘方弄到手
Help me get the secret formula
你们想喝多少根啤就有多少
and you can have as much root beer as you can drink
我痞老板要来取胜了
Victory, thy name is plankton
谢尔顿
章鱼哥先生
Well, Mr. Squidward
都快要关门了  连续好几小时
it's almost closing time, and we haven't seen
都没看到痞老板的眼睛或者触须
eye or antenna of old Plankton for hours
对啊  想必他这次总算是放弃
Yes, sir, I think this time, he's finally given up
注意了  蟹堡王的经营者
Attention, Krusty Krab management
我是你们的上级
This is your better speaking
什么
What?
我已经把这家餐厅包围了
I have the restaurant surrounded
把秘密配方给我
Give me the secret formula
不然我就毁掉蟹堡王
or I'll destroy The Krusty Krab
就你一个能拿我怎么样  臭虫
You and what army, bug?
就我一个吗
What army?
看看你四周  老螃蟹
Look around you, Krabs
你种了草吗
You planted grass?
草
Grass?
你绝对不会得逞的  痞老板
You'll never get away with it, Plankton
确实
You're right
水管太窄了
the pipes are much too narrow
更何况我真正想要的是蟹黄堡秘方
Besides, what I really want is the Krabby Patty formula
你还是算了吧
Well, you might as well forget it
秘方就锁在我保险柜里
The formula is locked away in me safe
我绝对不会告诉你密码多少
and I'll never give you the combination
闭嘴
Silence
你应该会发现
I think you'll find
我们完全有能力自己解开密码吧
we're more than capable of
figuring it out for ourselves
小的们
Oh, boys?
就这样
That's it
往左一点点
A little to the left
我诅咒你  痞老板
Curse you plankton
还有你们合体变成人耳的能力
and your ability to join together
to form a working human ear
好耶
Hot dog
好
Yes
我的了
It's mine
秘方是我的了
The formula's mine
过了这么多年  总算是我的了
After all these years, it's finally mine
我要昭告天下  今天
Let it be known that on this day
蟹黄堡秘方
我  谢尔顿痞老板
I, Sheldon J Plankton
单枪匹马推翻了蟹堡王
single-handedly overthrew The Krusty Krab
当然  还得到了家族的一点帮助
A-And of course, I had a little help from the family
痞老板  等等
Plankton, wait
你可不能看秘方啊
You can't look at the formula
求情没用的
Begging won't help
跟你说  你可绝对受不住真相
I'm telling you, you won't be able to handle the truth
世上有些东西
There's some things in this world
是一般人的双眼看不得的
that weren't meant for mortal eyes
独眼
Eye
管他呢
I don't care
击鼓吧
Drumroll, please
终于  过了这么多年
Finally, after all these years
总算能查明
I'm about to find out
蟹黄堡秘方
究竟是什么能让蟹黄堡这么好吃了
what makes a Krabby Patty taste so good
蟹黄堡的秘密配方就是
The secret recipe for one Krabby Patty is
一小撮盐
"A pinch of salt"
痞老板  等等
Plankton, wait
三茶匙洋葱碎
"three teaspoons of chopped onions"
我警告你了
I'm warning you
一杯爱
"a cup of love"
别看了
Don't do it
混合起来
"mixed together
最后再加上最重要的原料
"with the most important ingredient of all
四磅成堆的现磨
"four heaping pounds of freshly ground
浮游生物
plankton"?
都警告过你了
I warned you
你怎么不跑
Why ain't you running?
我不识字
Well, I can't read
滚出去
Get out of here
大伙儿
Hey, guys
我错过什么了没
Did I miss anything?
蟹老板  这真是蟹黄堡的秘密原料吗
Mr. Krabs, is this really
the secret ingredient for the Krabby Patty?
当然不是了
Of course not
痞老板多半会发现被骗了
And Plankton'll probably figure that out
马上回来找真正的秘方是什么
and be back again to find out what the real formula is
不过放心好了  小子们
But don't worry, boys
秘方安全得很
The formula's safe from harm
我把它藏到我最隐秘的藏身处了
I got it hidden in me most secret hiding place
所有人  就连痞老板都想不到这地方
A place no one, not even Plankton, would ever figure out
我猜猜看
Let me guess
就放在你家床垫底下
it's at home under your mattress
我诅咒你  章鱼哥
Curse you, Squidward